Dmitry Kuzmin

Software engineer

xotonic.dev · xotonic@yandex.com · linkedin.com/in/xotonic · github.com/xotonic

About me

Software engineer with 2+ years of work experience. Developing solutions in various fields from telecommunications management and marketing to cutting-edge researches of blockchain technology. Constantly investing in education and learning new tools for making better products. Seeking for further gaining and sharing experience as a software developer.

Experience

Blockchain developer, Remote • Sep 2018 - present • LuxCore

Designing, developing and functional testing a fraud-resistant decentralized exchange tightly integrated with Bitcoin blockchain.

Software engineer • Aug 2016 - Sep 2018 • Eltex

Developing data-rich front-end for B2B clients with dozens of pages for monitoring and configuration network devices, dashboards for both engineers and marketers. Maintaining and developing constantly scaling components of an accounting system, optimizing databases, collecting and analyzing metrics.

Education

Student • Sep 2015 - May 2016 • Additional programming courses

Linux system administration and kernel programming. Android app development.

Bachelor of Computer Science • Sep 2013 - Jul 2017 • Novosibirsk State Technical University, Russia Maintaining an educational system for creating PL compilers (online grammar editor). Administrating GitLab server for student's projects.

Skills

Technical skills

- Java: Maven, Gradle, Vaadin, Vert.X, Hazelcast, Spring, Tomcat, JUnit, Selenium, Swing.
- C++: boost, autotools, QT.
- SQL
- Python
- Databases: MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB.
- Blockchain: Bitcoin Script, Solidity.
- CI: Docker, Vagrant, Jenkins, Travis CI.
- Telecommunications: RADIUS, NETCONF.

Languages

- English: B2
- Russian: Native